<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: software | The Silence of the Lambs]]></title>
  <link href="http://isoyang.github.io/blog/categories/software/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://isoyang.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-25T14:49:04+03:00</updated>
  <id>http://isoyang.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[ISOYANG]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Install and Test OpenCV under Fedora/Ubuntu]]></title>
    <link href="http://isoyang.github.io/blog/2013/04/12/install-and-test-opencv-under-fedora-slash-ubuntu/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-12T19:36:00+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://isoyang.github.io/blog/2013/04/12/install-and-test-opencv-under-fedora-slash-ubuntu</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently, I attempted to install OpenCV in my laptop for  computer vision course. And I encountered some  problems during the process, but  finally  succeeded!
Here, I will briefly describe what I have done for the installation.
Important: make sure that the following packages have been installed</p>

<p><code>
yum list  packagename  # have a look at installed packages
</code>
<!--more-->
In Fedora 16 ,  the corresponding packages are <code>gtk2, pkgconfig</code> respectively
Dowload opencv source code (set 2.4.0 for instance) and uncompress it to your prefered directory:</p>

<p><code>
cd  your directory which will contain the source file
tar -xvf  OpenCV-2.4.0.tar.bz2
</code>
Next, go into the directory of OpenCV and establish a folder named release and enter it:</p>

<p><code>
cd  ~/OpenCV-2.4.0/
mkdir release
cd release
</code>
Now we are under the release folder and execute the following commands:</p>

<p><code>
cmake -D CMAKE_BUILD_TYPE=RELEASE -D CMAKE_INSTALL_PREFIX=/usr/local -D BUILD_PYTHON_SUPPORT=ON ..
</code>
This piece of code will produce makefiles for further processes. Then, we will enter codes in the terminal:</p>

<p><code>
make
sudo make install
</code>
If you have completed above steps,  some configurations should be made for correct use of OpenCV:</p>

<p><code>
sudo vim  /etc/ld.so.conf.d/opencv.conf
add /usr/local/lib into the file
sudo ldconfig
</code>
Furthermore, modify the path variable:</p>

<p><code>
sudo vim /etc/profile
add following contents
export PKG_CONFIG_PATH=/usr/local/lib/pkgconfig
export LD_LIBRARY_PATH=/usr/local/lib
</code></p>

<p>Save the file and quit, and have modifications come into practice now
or   ` source /etc/profile `
If these methods can not work,  you can logout and enter the system again.
The next part is to test whether openCV can function well.</p>

<p><code>
cd ~/OpenCV-2.4.0/samples/c
sh  build_all.sh
./facedetect  lena.jpg
</code>
If an image can pop up,  congratulations!  The library can work well!
<em>Notes</em>:
I have once got a problem when I try to test OpenCV:</p>

<p><code>OpenCV Error: Unspecified error (The function is not implemented. Rebuild the library with Windows, GTK+ 2.x or Carbon support. If you are on Ubuntu or Debian, install libgtk2.0-dev and pkg-config, then re-run cmake or configure script) in cvNamedWindow</code></p>

<p>I have the gtk2 installed, but the problem still remains.
And then I install the latest version of OpenCV source code. The problem have disappeared!!
OpenCV: old version is 2.3.1, and the current version is 2.4.0.</p>

<p><em>References</em>:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><a href="http://opencv.willowgarage.com/wiki/InstallGuide">http://opencv.willowgarage.com/wiki/InstallGuide</a></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a href="http://opencv.willowgarage.com/wiki/CompileOpenCVUsingLinux">http://opencv.willowgarage.com/wiki/CompileOpenCVUsingLinux</a></p>
  </li>
</ul>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
